paykun.com 2019-03-23

# PayKun • Privacy Policy | Secure Payment Gateway

### Scope of this Privacy Policy:

This privacy policy sets out how [https://paykun.com](https://paykun.com/) treats personally identifiable information collected from Merchants who use the Paykun.com payment gateway services, as well as consumer information that we acquire in the course of our business services. This Policy also covers the treatment of personally identifiable information that [PayKun.com's](https://paykun.com/) back end technology providers / partners may share with it.

This website has been designed for the purposes of collecting online payments. We collect and generate various data points about you. Data by which you are identified is termed as “Personal Data”. Personal Data does not mean information that is freely available or accessible in public domain. Your Privacy is of utmost importance to us and protection of your Personal Data is a key commitment for us.

We are governed by the provisions of applicable law in India including the Information Technology Act 2000 and the Information Technology (Reasonable security practices and procedures and sensitive personal data or information) Rules, 2011 to maintain the privacy of your Personal Data.

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) does not own or control, or to people that Paykun.com does not employ or manage.

### For Merchants:

**Paykun.com** takes privacy and data protection issues seriously. We have designed this Privacy Policy to explain how we handle personally identifiable information collected from Merchants who register for services and submit information to paykun.com through the Internet. If you have questions about paykun.com privacy practices, please contact us at **[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)**

Information security is critical to our business. We work to protect the security of your information. We store information gathered on secure computers. The number of employees involved in the management of the data center that have physical access to these computers is limited. We use advanced security technology to prevent our computers from being accessed by unauthorized persons. It is important for you (Merchant) to protect against unauthorized access to your Login ID/password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer and otherwise protect the password used to access the [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/)'s services.

Currently, [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) collects personal information on our Merchants, through the Merchant registration process, the service agreement that they execute and various submitted documents of the Merchant's creditability as required by [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) from time to time. [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) asks customers to supply various personal data when placing an order, such as name and address, telephone number, and E-mail address. [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) uses this data only for the purpose of filling an order, or communicating with the customer or Merchant about the status of an order. The Merchants however, are able to collect personal information on their customers via the purchases that are made. The data Paykun.com collects is used in the aggregate to give us demographic information about the entire [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) audience in order to improve the service to you and to our Merchants, to perform statistical analysis of the collective characteristics and behavior of our Merchants and visitors, to measure overall patron demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) domain and to analyze how and where to use our resources. We use cookies to help us determine which website user’s link to, and which services Merchants and visitors use.

We also track information like the domain name from which you contact us, the pages you request, the products you buy, the referring website, and the time that you spend on the website. For everyone who visits [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) Merchant purchase page, we log IP addresses, the type of operating system that your computer uses, and the type of browser software used by you. From the IP address, we can determine the Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of your point of connectivity.

If you are our registered Merchant then the personal information you provide - name, address, etc.- allows us to inform you about updates, or changes to the service and to notify you of services of Paykun.com, its backend service providers and affiliates that we believe may be of interest to you.

[PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) uses reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure and will not disclose this information to other individuals or organizations unless required by law. However, Paykun.com will exchange information with other companies and organizations for the sole purposes of fraud protection and risk reduction. However, in the case of abuse or breach of security, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties which receive the information illegally. Paykun.com will not distribute customer information to be used in mailing lists, surveys, or any other purpose other than what is required to perform our services. However, Paykun.com will send personally identifiable information about you (Merchants) to other companies or people when: 

  1. we have your consent to share the information.
  2. we need to share your information to provide the service you have requested.
  3. we need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) to provide a service to you (unless we tell you differently these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide them beyond what is necessary to assist us).

Personally identifiable consumer information is also shared with third parties (such as our Acquiring banks and credit card processors) to the extent necessary for [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) to deliver payment-processing services. [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) is committed to safeguard the privacy of our customers' personal data. [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/) may also link to a wide variety of other sites. We are not responsible for their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users.

If you (i.e. our registered Merchant) would like to view the information we have collected from you and your customers or you want to correct your information or the billing/shipping details of your customers or their IP addresses, please go to Merchant Login page and log into your account to view the above details and to review your personal information. If you have questions or suggestions, we can be reached by email at **[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)** or by writing to us at:

##### PayKun Payment Solutions Private Limited.

304, Govardhan Plaza,

Ghogha Circle,

Bhavnagar – 364001, Gujarat, India

We respond to subpoenas, warrants, or other court orders regarding information that is contained within our access logs concerning any registered Merchant, customer or visitor. We reserve the right to release that information concerning any registered Merchant who we believe is in violation of our content guidelines, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. We cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our servers and services for illegal activities. We also reserve the right to report any illegal activity by our Merchants or their customers to law enforcement for prosecution.

Please be aware that Paykun.com does not control the acts of its Merchants or visitors. All Merchants, customers and visitors should be aware that, when they disclose personal information such as their actual name, store's name, e-mail address, etc. to third parties, the information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties, outside of [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/). In the event that you encounter any [PayKun.com](https://paykun.com/), Merchant who is improperly collecting or using information about users, please contact us by emailing at: **[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)**

If you feel that Paykun.com has violated this Statement on Privacy in any way, please contact us at **[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)** that we may address this issue.

### For Customers:

PayKun a brand operating under **PayKun Payment Solutions Private Limited** (we/us/our) take privacy and data protection issues seriously. We have designed this Privacy Policy to explain how we handle personally identifiable information collected from Customers/Users (you/ your) who use services of PayKun directly or through any third party, submit information to PayKun through the Internet. If you have questions about PayKun privacy practices, please contact us at **[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)**

PayKun being a responsible organisation acknowledge the importance of right to privacy. Customers all over India place their trust on us by transacting though PayKun and we at PayKun values that trust. And we are committed to protect and safeguard your personal data.

This Policy also covers the treatment of personally identifiable information that PayKun back end technology providers/partners may share with it. This document describes the usage of your personal data acquired by PayKun. 

This Policy sets out how we will use and protect your information. We will use your personal information only for the purposes and in the manner allowed by the applicable data protection laws. We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy carefully.

  1. ### 1\. The information we collect:

PayKun asks Customers to supply various personal data when placing an online order, such as name and address, telephone number, and E-mail address. We collect Customers name, contact details, and customers Debit/Credit Card Details and other details as per several payment options. (we collect the Debit/Credit Card details and other payment details, as per the rules and regulation law, established by the Reserve Bank of India and Card Companies). In addition to curb down the chance of risk and fraud we also collect information from Customer’s computer, phone, tablet or other device Customers are using to access our services. This includes the IP address, the browser, and Customer’s language settings. There are also situations in which we receive information about Customer from others or automatically collect other information. This is the basic overview of the information we collect.

We may also receive information about you from other sources. These include business partners, such as affiliate partners, and other independent third parties, and anything we get from them may be combined with information provided by you.

  2. ### 2\. What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service and create a picture of your interests. This will allow us to understand our customers and visitors better, so we can make our services and marketing more relevant. Information that we use in this way may include: 

    * Internal record keeping.
    * We may use the information to improve our products and services. 
    * Information about your use of this site.
    * To help improve our Applications and our Services.
    * To provide you with customer care.
    * For security and fraud prevention purposes.
    * We may periodically send promotional e-mails about new products, package and special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
    * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by e-mail, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customize the website according to your interests. We can SMS you about latest package offer, your package renovation date and charges etc. If you do not want to receive e-mail or SMS from us, other than order notifications and receipts, please adjust your “Subscription” preferences by logging into your account.
  3. ### 3\. Sharing of Data

We currently share your personal data, where necessary, with the following recipients: 

    * You and, where you request, any third party you ask us to share it with.
    * Acquiring Banks, PayKun Merchants and Facility providers.
    * Governmental, legal, regulatory, or similar authorities, on request or where required, including for the purposes of reporting any actual or suspected breach of applicable law or regulation.
    * Direct marketing service providers.
    * Data analytics service providers.
    * Third party service providers used for the delivery of some aspects of the Services (e.g. SMS delivery, email delivery, web notifications, app notifications and phone number lookup).

Our Applications may, interface with third party services that you have previously interacted with (e.g. Facebook), or contain links to third party content. Please note that PayKun is not responsible for such services or content, or the privacy policies associated with those services or content. We recommend that you review any third party’s privacy policy before accessing such services or content. 

  4. ### 4\. Links to other websites:

Our site contains links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Customer should consult the other sites' privacy policy as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

  5. ### 5\. Control of Data:

Customer has all the right and control over their personal data provided to us. Customer can request us for an overview of their data by putting up a mail to us. In certain situations, you can ask us to modify, erase, or block or restrict the processing of, the personal data we hold about you, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal data and we rely on you to ensure that your personal data is complete, accurate and current. Please do inform us promptly of any changes to or inaccuracies of your personal data by contacting us.

PayKun want customers to be in control of how personal data is used by us. Customers can do this in following ways: 

    1. You can ask us for a copy of the personal data we hold about that particular individual.
    2. You can inform us of any changes to their personal data, or can ask us to correct any of the personal data we hold about them.
    3. An individual can ask us to erase, or block or restrict the processing of, the personal data we hold about them, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal data.
    4. In certain situations, individual can also ask us to send the personal data, we have given to a third party.

Where we are using personal data on the basis of individual’s consent, he/she is entitled to withdraw that consent at any time subject to applicable law. Moreover, where we process personal data based on legitimate interest or the public interest, individual have the right to object at any time to that use of personal data subject to applicable law.

If you wish to object to the processing of your personal data on the basis of legitimate interest and no opt-out mechanism is available, please contact us at **[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)**

  6. ### 6\. Security of Your Personal Data:

As stated above we are heavily regulated body and our operation are monitored by the Reserve Bank of India, Acquiring Bank and Card Companies. We abide by the provisions of Indian Information Technology Act 2000 and its Rules and all relevant amendments, we also have the certification of PCI DSS (a set of rules and regulation by the Card Companies). PayKun protects, processes and uses all the data collected in accordance with the applicable Data Protection Laws.

PayKun observe reasonable procedures to prevent unauthorized access to, and the misuse of, personal data collected by PayKun.

We use appropriate business systems and procedures to protect and safeguard the personal data given to us. We also use security procedures and technical and physical restrictions for accessing and using the personal data on our servers. Only authorized personnel are permitted to access personal data in the course of their work.

We will retain your personal data for as long as we deem it necessary to enable you to use our services, to provide our services to you (including maintaining the online user account (if created)), to comply with applicable laws, resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business, including to detect and prevent fraud or other illegal activities. All personal data we retain will be subject to this Privacy Policy. If you have a question about a specific retention period for certain types of personal data we process about you, please contact us via the contact details provided below: **[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)**.

  7. ### 7\. Business Transfers:

As PayKun continue to develop its business, we might sell or otherwise transfer certain of our assets. In such transactions, user information, including Personal Information, is generally one of the transferred business assets, and by providing your Personal Information to us you agree that your data may be transferred to such parties in these circumstances.

  8. ### 8\. Cookies:

Our website uses cookies. A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of the browser on your computer's hard disk so that the website can remember who you are. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site and services.

#### We may use cookies in the following ways:

    * Where they are essential to make our site work.
    * To enable the personalization features on our site (which give you the ability to recall recently viewed pages and see information which you have input on line).
    * To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our site and to help us improve the structure of our site. We cannot identify you personally in this way.
  9. ### 9\. How to contact us:

If you have any questions or concerns about the privacy policy of PayKun or its implementation, you may contact us through our Grievance Officer. If at any time you decide that we should no longer hold any of your personal data, or wish to correct your information or the billing/shipping details, you can mail us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) PayKun.com or write to us at:

##### PayKun Payment Solutions Private Limited.(Corporate Office)

304, Govardhan Plaza,

Ghogha Circle,

Bhavnagar – 364001, Gujarat, India

##### Grievance Officer:

In accordance with the Information Technology Act, 2000 and the Information Technology (Intermediaries Guidelines) Rules, 2011 made thereunder, the name and contact details of the Grievance Officer are provided below:

##### Mr. Nirav Solanki (10:00AM TO 05:30PM)

Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Contact No.: 1800 212 8070
